<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The RAW and The COOKED - cooked_events</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/feeds/cooked_events.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/</id><updated>2018-09-29T19:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Live Electronic Performances</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/live.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-29T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T19:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2018-09-29:/live.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Andrea Guidi,
Eddie Wade,
Loraine James,
Ewa Justka,
Tom Gurion,
James Doherty,
Lia Mice,
7xins,
Wandering Oscillators,
Paul Hierophant,
A Colder Consciousness...
and more TBC.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Andrea Guidi,
Eddie Wade,
Loraine James,
Ewa Justka,
Tom Gurion,
James Doherty,
Lia Mice,
7xins,
Wandering Oscillators,
Paul Hierophant,
A Colder Consciousness...
and more TBC.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Ewa Justka</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/keynote_ewa_justka.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-29T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T17:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2018-09-29:/keynote_ewa_justka.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Acid and DIY gabber electronics.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ewa Justka is a polish electronic acid-technoise artist (oh, how edgy), self taught instruments builder and electronics teacher based in London. She is also interested in the notion of materiality of objects, vibrant, ontological systems (human bodies, electronic circuits, integrated circuits: varied range of micro and macro environments and relations between them) and an investigation of modes of quasi-direct perception through extreme light and sound actions, electronics, hardware hacking, breaking, deconstructing, wiring - or, to put it bluntly - designing synths and playing hard techno. Ewa has performed and led workshops at festivals and venues like: Loop Festival, Sonic Acts, Supernormal Festival, Club Transmediale, STEIM, Colour out of Space, Unsound Festival, Norberg Festival, Insomnia Festial, Cafe Oto, and more.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Tom Whitwell</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/keynote_tom_whitwell.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-29T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T16:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2018-09-29:/keynote_tom_whitwell.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How to design a module when you have never designed one before.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;DIY Modular guru Tom Whitwell from &lt;a href="https://musicthing.co.uk/"&gt;Music Thing Modular&lt;/a&gt; discusses designing your first modular unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Whitwell designs DIY musical instruments as Music Thing Modular. He created the enormously popular Turing Machine, Mikrophonie and Radio Music modules for Eurorack Synthesiser, which are open-source designs inspired by early experimental electronic music. He's a former journalist and magazine editor who taught himself electronics after attending a workshop by Tom Bugs on Brick Lane. In his talk, Tom tells the story of how he got started designing his first module, from experimentation and prototyping to design and (distributed) mass production.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>QMUL Talk - Giacomo Lepri</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/talk_giacomo_lepri.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-29T15:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T15:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2018-09-29:/talk_giacomo_lepri.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Composer and researcher Giacomo Lepri will introduce the ideas behind the Cembalo Scrivano: an interactive audiovisual installation based on an augmented typewriter. The talk will focus on Media Archaeology and Technology Remediation as strategies for the creation of interactive experiences and ambiguous designs.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Composer and researcher Giacomo Lepri will introduce the ideas behind the Cembalo Scrivano: an interactive audiovisual installation based on an augmented typewriter. The talk will focus on Media Archaeology and Technology Remediation as strategies for the creation of interactive experiences and ambiguous designs.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>QMUL Talk - Lia Mice</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/talk_lia_mice.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-29T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T15:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2018-09-29:/talk_lia_mice.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Producer, DJ, and instrument designer Lia Mice discusses drawing inspiration from science-fiction to explore how the sampler is a time machine - interacting with the past, present and future, and the experiments that are the foundation of her upcoming LP The Sampler As A Time Machine, out November 9 on Optimo …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Producer, DJ, and instrument designer Lia Mice discusses drawing inspiration from science-fiction to explore how the sampler is a time machine - interacting with the past, present and future, and the experiments that are the foundation of her upcoming LP The Sampler As A Time Machine, out November 9 on Optimo Music.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Break</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/break.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-29T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T14:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2018-09-29:/break.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html"></content></entry><entry><title>Bela</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/workshop_bela.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-29T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T12:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2018-09-29:/workshop_bela.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://bela.io/"&gt;bela&lt;/a&gt; team show you how to make an ultra low latency Digital Musial Instrument.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This hands-on workshop introduces &lt;a href="http://bela.io"&gt;Bela&lt;/a&gt;, an embedded maker platform for responsive audio and sensor processing. Bela can be used to create digital musical instruments, synthesisers, and other interactive projects, which can be developed in C/C++, Pure Data (Pd) or Supercollider, amongst other languages. The platform features an on-board browser-based IDE and oscilloscope for getting started quickly, onboard examples and documentation, and online community resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop will focus on creating interactive music projects using Pd. Participants will be guided through some simple circuit-building and Pd programming activities. Bela kits, breadboards, sensors and other electronics will be provided for use during the workshop. Participants should bring their own laptop (any platform) and a pair of headphones.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>GMSN!</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/workshop_gmsn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-29T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T10:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2018-09-29:/workshop_gmsn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://gmsn.co.uk/"&gt;GMSN!&lt;/a&gt;'s Rob Spencer walks you through building your own modular synth unit.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;GMSN! is an Open Source Synth designer based in Glasgow. PCBs, panels and other accessories are available at &lt;a href="https://gmsn.co.uk/"&gt;gmsn.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;, with all support related chat at &lt;a href="https://forum.gmsn.co.uk/"&gt;forum.gmsn.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Pure. Open. Modular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workshop participants will be taking the raw materials of a PCB and components and cooking up a GMSN! Pure Digit, a small programmable utility Eurorack module. Once the hardware is complete, the software, which includes cool programs such as RandomSequencer, ClockDivider, BasslineGenerator and BitCrusher, will be uploaded to the module. This will be a workshop in SMD Soldering using the hotplate method and all tools and components will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please buy your kits in advance &lt;a href="https://gmsn.co.uk/product/inter-sections-synth-building-workshop/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>