<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The RAW and The COOKED - cooked_artists</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/feeds/cooked_artists.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/</id><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>7XINS</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/7xins.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/7xins.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Releasing under his 7XINS alias, Ben solely operates as a producer of live electronic music, built on a manipulation of machinery and hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Residing from a post industrial town of South Wales, and with a background in mechanical engineering and electronics, Ben’s transition into audio electronics has been a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Releasing under his 7XINS alias, Ben solely operates as a producer of live electronic music, built on a manipulation of machinery and hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Residing from a post industrial town of South Wales, and with a background in mechanical engineering and electronics, Ben’s transition into audio electronics has been a very natural one, having developed a healthy obsession with machines and the intricacies of sound since his early discovery of hard house and rave culture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now deeply involved in London’s dance music scene with a demanding position on Egg LDN’s team whilst also working on 7XINS productions, a rolling rich analogous sound with a strong sense of depth and atmosphere remains his trademark.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>A Colder Consciousness</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/a_colder_consciousness.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/a_colder_consciousness.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Colder Consciousness is a radio show run by Flora Pitrolo, broadcasting dark underground electronic music, mostly archival, since 2011 on London’s Resonance FM and on Skopje’s Kanal 103. She plays at a number of dark synth, industrial, techno and goth parties in London, runs a series of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Colder Consciousness is a radio show run by Flora Pitrolo, broadcasting dark underground electronic music, mostly archival, since 2011 on London’s Resonance FM and on Skopje’s Kanal 103. She plays at a number of dark synth, industrial, techno and goth parties in London, runs a series of nights at The Glove That Fits and the record label ACC Records.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>AN ALIEN</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/an_alien.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/an_alien.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An Alien is the brand new music project of Andrea Guidi. Artist and designer of sounding instruments, Andrea composed and produced electronic music with Orax and Too Young To Love (signed to EMI Publishing and released by different labels between 2009 and 2011). A short list of the festival where …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An Alien is the brand new music project of Andrea Guidi. Artist and designer of sounding instruments, Andrea composed and produced electronic music with Orax and Too Young To Love (signed to EMI Publishing and released by different labels between 2009 and 2011). A short list of the festival where he performed includes: Isle of Wight Festival 2011 (Strongbow Tent), Exit Festival 2010, and many UK festivals like Kendal Calling and Offset Festival. After seven years of silence, An Alien emerged from an hacked server full of political memes and travelled via a cloud to the UK. It just connected to London.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Giacomo Lepri</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/giacomo_lepri.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/giacomo_lepri.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Giacomo Lepri is a musician, improviser, composer, sonic interaction designer and researcher. His work involves the development of interactive systems for music performances and audiovisual installations. Giacomo's music practice stands out for the combination of object augmentation, algorithmic composition, soundscape exploration, electronic synthesis and a bit of magic.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Giacomo Lepri is a musician, improviser, composer, sonic interaction designer and researcher. His work involves the development of interactive systems for music performances and audiovisual installations. Giacomo's music practice stands out for the combination of object augmentation, algorithmic composition, soundscape exploration, electronic synthesis and a bit of magic.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Lia Mice</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/lia_mice.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/lia_mice.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lia Mice’s live sets incorporate custom designed instruments and live voice sampling, bringing new dimensions to the analog sampler live set. She has performed live in the UK and internationally at venues including The Tate Modern London, The Empty Bottle Chicago and WOMB Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lia Mice’s live sets incorporate custom designed instruments and live voice sampling, bringing new dimensions to the analog sampler live set. She has performed live in the UK and internationally at venues including The Tate Modern London, The Empty Bottle Chicago and WOMB Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Paul Hierophant</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/paul_hierophant.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/paul_hierophant.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;DJ, Producer and owner of Hierophant Records. Playing live improvised ambient, electro and techno music using modular synthesisers. Dedicated to underground culture.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;DJ, Producer and owner of Hierophant Records. Playing live improvised ambient, electro and techno music using modular synthesisers. Dedicated to underground culture.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Tom Gurion</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/tom_gurion.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/tom_gurion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tom is a musician and researcher. After many years playing bass guitar in rock bands, he recently started developing an improvised live electronic set with hardware synths, focusing on percussive, fast, and poly-metric structures.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tom is a musician and researcher. After many years playing bass guitar in rock bands, he recently started developing an improvised live electronic set with hardware synths, focusing on percussive, fast, and poly-metric structures.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Tom Whitwell</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/tom_whitwell.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/tom_whitwell.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tom Whitwell designs DIY musical instruments as Music Thing Modular. He created the enormously popular Turing Machine, Mikrophonie and Radio Music modules for Eurorack Synthesiser, which are open-source designs inspired by early experimental electronic music. He's a former journalist and magazine editor who taught himself electronics after attending a workshop …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tom Whitwell designs DIY musical instruments as Music Thing Modular. He created the enormously popular Turing Machine, Mikrophonie and Radio Music modules for Eurorack Synthesiser, which are open-source designs inspired by early experimental electronic music. He's a former journalist and magazine editor who taught himself electronics after attending a workshop by Tom Bugs on Brick Lane. In his talk, Tom tells the story of how he got started designing his first module, from experimentation and prototyping to design and (distributed) mass production.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Wandering Oscillators</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/wandering_oscillators.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/wandering_oscillators.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wandering Oscillators is a one off collaboration by Jon Pigrem (The Third Eye) and James Weaver (Gyratory System and Blick | Trio). Building from a series of improvisations using modular synths and live instruments they will be presenting an downbeat electronic soundscape which blends washes of ambient and appropriated sounds with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wandering Oscillators is a one off collaboration by Jon Pigrem (The Third Eye) and James Weaver (Gyratory System and Blick | Trio). Building from a series of improvisations using modular synths and live instruments they will be presenting an downbeat electronic soundscape which blends washes of ambient and appropriated sounds with propulsive rhythms and retro drum machines.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>