<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The RAW and The COOKED - day</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/feeds/day.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/</id><updated>2018-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The COOKED</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/cooked.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2018-09-29:/cooked.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The COOKED focuses on DIY instrument and modular building, and features hands on workshops to make and develop your own musical instrument or synthesizer module. The day leads into a night of live electronic performance, featuring some of the leading lights in DIY creativity, electronic trickery and new and alternative approaches to live performance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The COOKED focuses on DIY instrument and modular building, and features hands on workshops to make and develop your own musical instrument or synthesizer module. The Bela team guide you through the process of using their lightning fast single board computer to make low latency interactive prototypes, and GMSN! will be on site to supervise the construction of one of their newest eurorack modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will also be trade stands from some of the UK’s leading modular outlets, and modular systems to learn and experiment on and keynote presentations from experts in the instrument and modular world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day leads into a night of live electronic performance, featuring some of the leading lights in DIY creativity, electronic trickey and new and alternative approaches to live performance. &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The RAW</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/raw.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2018-09-28:/raw.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The RAW focusses on Live Coding and code based approaches to the real time creation of sound and image. The day features workshops and presentations by experienced live coders, rounded off with an Algorave - a live coded audio visual spectacular featuring performances from some of the UK's leading lights in audio visual coded performance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The RAW focusses on Live Coding and code based approaches to the real time creation of sound and image. For those yet to make its acquaintance, Live Coding is the creation of sonic or visual content generated through the execution of computer code in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The daytime part of the event features workshops hosted by experienced live coders, where newcomers will be guided through the processes in a practical environment, leading to an effective working knowledge of the practice. Experienced users will be able to build on existing skills, branch out into new applications and develop a greater understanding of the craft guided by lightning presentations from experienced performers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day rounds off with an Algorave, a live coded audio visual spectacular featuring performances from some of the UK's leading lights in audio visual coded performance.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>