<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The RAW and The COOKED - raw_artists</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/feeds/raw_artists.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/</id><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>0001 - Gerard Roma</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/0001-gerard-roma.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/0001-gerard-roma.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;0001 is a project that explores live coding of low-information signals as an improvisational practice. Binary oscillators are combined and modulated to create complex textures and rhythms.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;0001 is a project that explores live coding of low-information signals as an improvisational practice. Binary oscillators are combined and modulated to create complex textures and rhythms.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Alo Allik</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/alo-allik.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/alo-allik.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Alo is an Estonian artist who has performed his live coded electronic music and generative computer graphics throughout the world. His aesthetically and geographically restless lifestyle has enabled him to traverse a diverse range of musical worlds including DJ-ing electronic dance music, live electronic jam sessions, electroacoustic composition, free improvisation …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Alo is an Estonian artist who has performed his live coded electronic music and generative computer graphics throughout the world. His aesthetically and geographically restless lifestyle has enabled him to traverse a diverse range of musical worlds including DJ-ing electronic dance music, live electronic jam sessions, electroacoustic composition, free improvisation and audiovisual performances. He has forged collaborations with a number of curious and innovative musicians, writers and visual artists along the way focussed on exploring links between technology, creativity and tradition. In recent years he has been actively participating in the Algorave movement developing a style he describes as noisefunk which combines traditional rhythm patterns with evolutionary synthesis algorithms. Currently, Alo works as a researcher and a lecturer in music technology in London, while continuing to perform his music and visuals to audiences worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>hellocatfood</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/hellocatfood.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/hellocatfood.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;hellocatfood is the alias of Antonio Roberts, a visual artist based in Birmingham, UK. For his live visuals he (mis)uses a range of programming languages to create glitched, broken visuals. He has provided visuals for MTV, Com Truise, Blood Sport, Steve Davis, and My Panda Shall Fly.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;hellocatfood is the alias of Antonio Roberts, a visual artist based in Birmingham, UK. For his live visuals he (mis)uses a range of programming languages to create glitched, broken visuals. He has provided visuals for MTV, Com Truise, Blood Sport, Steve Davis, and My Panda Shall Fly.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>⎷p38</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/p38.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/p38.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;⎷p38 is a musician and multimedia artist. Their work is concerned with perception, the relationship between the ‘real’ and the ‘virtual’, the ‘digital’ and the ‘acoustic’. Sound is seen as an inextricable aspect of space and ⎷p38 is interested our relationship to new technologies of communication and creation. They involve …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;⎷p38 is a musician and multimedia artist. Their work is concerned with perception, the relationship between the ‘real’ and the ‘virtual’, the ‘digital’ and the ‘acoustic’. Sound is seen as an inextricable aspect of space and ⎷p38 is interested our relationship to new technologies of communication and creation. They involve a personal ethnographic method and have a degree in Anthropology. They have Indian and British heritage, and always consider the eternal vibration of Hindustani sound. They like thinking about multidimensional metaphysical space and the nuances of language. They are currently studying for a MA in Computational Arts.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>