<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The RAW and The COOKED - raw_artists</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/feeds/raw_artists.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/</id><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>0001 - Gerard Roma</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/0001.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/0001.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;0001 is a project that explores live coding of low-information signals as an improvisational practice. Binary oscillators are combined and modulated to create complex textures and rhythms.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;0001 is a project that explores live coding of low-information signals as an improvisational practice. Binary oscillators are combined and modulated to create complex textures and rhythms.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Alo</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/alo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/alo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Alo is an Estonian artist who has performed his live coded electronic music and generative computer graphics throughout the world. His aesthetically and geographically restless lifestyle has enabled him to traverse a diverse range of musical worlds including DJ-ing electronic dance music, live electronic jam sessions, electroacoustic composition, free improvisation …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Alo is an Estonian artist who has performed his live coded electronic music and generative computer graphics throughout the world. His aesthetically and geographically restless lifestyle has enabled him to traverse a diverse range of musical worlds including DJ-ing electronic dance music, live electronic jam sessions, electroacoustic composition, free improvisation and audiovisual performances. He has forged collaborations with a number of curious and innovative musicians, writers and visual artists along the way focussed on exploring links between technology, creativity and tradition. In recent years he has been actively participating in the Algorave movement developing a style he describes as noisefunk which combines traditional rhythm patterns with evolutionary synthesis algorithms. Currently, Alo works as a researcher and a lecturer in music technology in London, while continuing to perform his music and visuals to audiences worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Can Ince</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/can_ince.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/can_ince.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Can Ince is a musician, developer, and researcher based in the UK. He utilizes a live-coding tracker to explore uncharted sonic-scapes while drawing sounds from electro and braindance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Can Ince is a musician, developer, and researcher based in the UK. He utilizes a live-coding tracker to explore uncharted sonic-scapes while drawing sounds from electro and braindance.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Erik Nyström</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/erik_nystrom.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/erik_nystrom.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Erik Nyström composes computer music for live and fixed media. His current work uses multichannel sound synthesis and interactive algorithmic systems to explore artificial materiality and postnatural environments in sound. He performs worldwide and his music has been released on the Canadian label empreintes DIGITALes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Erik Nyström composes computer music for live and fixed media. His current work uses multichannel sound synthesis and interactive algorithmic systems to explore artificial materiality and postnatural environments in sound. He performs worldwide and his music has been released on the Canadian label empreintes DIGITALes.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>hellocatfood</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/hellocatfood.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/hellocatfood.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;hellocatfood is the alias of Antonio Roberts, a visual artist based in Birmingham, UK. For his live visuals he (mis)uses a range of programming languages to create glitched, broken visuals. He has provided visuals for MTV, Com Truise, Blood Sport, Steve Davis, and My Panda Shall Fly.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;hellocatfood is the alias of Antonio Roberts, a visual artist based in Birmingham, UK. For his live visuals he (mis)uses a range of programming languages to create glitched, broken visuals. He has provided visuals for MTV, Com Truise, Blood Sport, Steve Davis, and My Panda Shall Fly.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>hmurd</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/hmurd.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/hmurd.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;hmurd generally makes music with code. He is part of Music Hackspace and Cherche Encore. He recently released an EP with Co-Dependent.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;hmurd generally makes music with code. He is part of Music Hackspace and Cherche Encore. He recently released an EP with Co-Dependent.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Hortense</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/hortense.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/hortense.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Blue Maignien (they/them) performs as Hortense - a name given at birth - by generating sound with code using TidalCycles and sometimes writing about mental health distress. Blue is part of Cherche Encore - a record label and series of event - with Harry Murdoch. In the future, Blue would like to keep …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Blue Maignien (they/them) performs as Hortense - a name given at birth - by generating sound with code using TidalCycles and sometimes writing about mental health distress. Blue is part of Cherche Encore - a record label and series of event - with Harry Murdoch. In the future, Blue would like to keep making radio and contribute to building caring sonic environment. &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>⎷p38</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/p38.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/p38.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;⎷p38 is a musician and multimedia artist. Their work is concerned with perception, the relationship between the ‘real’ and the ‘virtual’, the ‘digital’ and the ‘acoustic’. Sound is seen as an inextricable aspect of space and ⎷p38 is interested our relationship to new technologies of communication and creation. They involve …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;⎷p38 is a musician and multimedia artist. Their work is concerned with perception, the relationship between the ‘real’ and the ‘virtual’, the ‘digital’ and the ‘acoustic’. Sound is seen as an inextricable aspect of space and ⎷p38 is interested our relationship to new technologies of communication and creation. They involve a personal ethnographic method and have a degree in Anthropology. They have Indian and British heritage, and always consider the eternal vibration of Hindustani sound. They like thinking about multidimensional metaphysical space and the nuances of language. They are currently studying for a MA in Computational Arts.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>peterMann - Anna Xambó</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/petermann.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/petermann.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Anna Xambó (aka peterMann) is an experimental electronic music producer and researcher. Her musical practice includes live coding, multichannel spatialization, tangible music, collaborative interfaces, audience participation with mobile devices, and real-time music information retrieval. To date, she has released three solo recordings: “init” (2010, Carpal Tunnel), “On the Go” (2013 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Anna Xambó (aka peterMann) is an experimental electronic music producer and researcher. Her musical practice includes live coding, multichannel spatialization, tangible music, collaborative interfaces, audience participation with mobile devices, and real-time music information retrieval. To date, she has released three solo recordings: “init” (2010, Carpal Tunnel), “On the Go” (2013, Carpal Tunnel) and "H2RI" (2018, pan y rosas). She is currently an associate professor in music technology at the music department of the Norwegian University of Science and Technology (NTNU) and a collaborator at the Centre for Digital Music, Queen Mary University of London, working on the design and evaluation of new tools for music production and performance within the EU-funded project AudioCommons.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Renick Bell</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/renick_bell.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/renick_bell.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tokyo-based Renick Bell improvises bass-heavy algorithmically-generated music full of percussion and noise by live coding with open source software, including software he has written called Conductive. This year he has released albums on Rabit's Halcyon Veil label and Seagrave Records. In 2016 he released an EP on Lee Gamble's UIQ …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tokyo-based Renick Bell improvises bass-heavy algorithmically-generated music full of percussion and noise by live coding with open source software, including software he has written called Conductive. This year he has released albums on Rabit's Halcyon Veil label and Seagrave Records. In 2016 he released an EP on Lee Gamble's UIQ label. His music practice corresponds with a research practice of writing software and writing research papers on live coding, electronic music, and art, as well as teaching in university and other contexts.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>TYPE</title><link href="https://therawandthecooked.intersections.io/type.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Gurion</name></author><id>tag:therawandthecooked.intersections.io,2000-01-01:/type.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Yorkshire Programming Ensemble (TYPE) is a collection of humans, Lucy Cheesman, Laurie Johnson, and Ryan Kirkbride, that meet IRL and URL and enjoy exploring rhythmic music in a collaborative virtual space and generally making a lot of noise. We work collaboratively in a shared text buffer using software called …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Yorkshire Programming Ensemble (TYPE) is a collection of humans, Lucy Cheesman, Laurie Johnson, and Ryan Kirkbride, that meet IRL and URL and enjoy exploring rhythmic music in a collaborative virtual space and generally making a lot of noise. We work collaboratively in a shared text buffer using software called Troop and each member of TYPE constructs portions of music-generating code before interacting with the work one another has left behind. By making and unmaking each other’s code TYPE works both together and against each other in the exploration of sound and rhythms.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>